Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1783-1817 (Box 1-6)
  - Barnhart, John Hendley, 1871-?, 1931 February 25-1936 Dec. 22; 4 items
    - "John Bartram's First Interest in Botany", Reprint, 3p.
      Reprinted from Bartonia Special Issue, 1931
    - to Mrs. John Ross Delafield, 1936 February 25; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. Delafield, 1936 December 22; ALS, 1p.
  - Barnwell, William, 1801 May 06; 1item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 May 06; ALS, 4p.
  - Barstow, Seth T., 1809 March 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 March 25; ALS, 3p.
  - (to Mrs. Barton?), 1815 February 20; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Re: David Rittenhouse, n.d.; 1 item
    - to unknown, AN, 1p.
  - Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815, 1791 April 15-1814 June 17; 16 items
    Folder consists of hand-written field notes and botanical observations.
    - notes from M.S.S. Journal, ANS, 2p.
    - notes from William Bartram's journal, Ams, 1p.
    - Memoir, PrD, 69p.
    - to unknown, 1783 May 27; ALS, 4p.
    - "A Memoir concerning the Fascinating Faculty which has been ascribed...", 1796 February 02; PrD, 88p.
    - Proposals for printing by subscription, Elements of Zoology, 1806 October 14; Broadside, 1p.
    - to unknown., 1806; ALS, 1p.
    - to unknown, 1808 May; ALS, 1p.
    - Memo, 1809, June 23; ANS, 1p.
    - to unknown, 1810 May 11810 May 1; ALS, 2p.
    - to unknown, 1811 November 15; ALS, 1p.
    - to unknown, 1812 September; ALS, 2p.
    - to unknown, 1813 March; ALS, 9p.
    - to unknown, 1815 February 01; ALS, 1p.
    - "On Elephantine Bones", n.d.; Book page,
      About salt-licks.
    - "On Elephantine Bones", n.d.; Book page, 1p.
      Account of the discovery of a "Mammoth" stomach in Virginia.
    - "Preparing for the Press, The Anatomy and Physiology of the Rattle-...", Broadside
    - List of signatures, presumably related to the proposal, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
    - "Barton's Zoology", n.d.; Newspaper clipping, 1p.
      About Barton's "Element of Botany."
  - Barton, David Rittenhouse, 1783-1837, 1806 September 29-1817 Aug. 1817; 4 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September 29; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 February 02; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 August 3; ALS, 1p.
    - to Mary Barton, 1817; ALS, 1p.
  - Barton, H., 1811 March 17; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 March 17; ALS, 2p.
  - Barton, Mary, n.d.; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Barton, Matthias (brother of Benjamin Smith Barton), 1804 October 24-1807 Jan. 6; 6 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 October 24; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806; ALS, 2p.
      This letter was thought to be written to William but BSB refers to fish drawings which are in progress by Matthias
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 January 06; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin SmithBarton, n.d.; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Barton, Matthias (nephew of Benjamin Smith Barton), 1810 March 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 March 12; ALS, 1p.
  - Barton, Richard Peter, ?-1821, 1806 September 22-1815 Feb. 9; 8 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September 22; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 April 06; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 November 27; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 26; ALS, 15p.
      A fascinating letter from Barton's brother covering a dizzying array of topics: trees, dyes, birds, soil, plants, maple sugar, etc.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 February 06; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 January 19; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 February 09; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 February 09; ALS, 3p.
  - Barton, Robert R., 1814 March 22; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Barton, Sarah, 1801 November 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 November 23; ALS, 2p.
  - Barton, Thomas B., 1809 April 03-1815 Jan. 19; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 April 3; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 January 19; ALS, 3p.
  - Barton, Thomas P., 1803-1869, n.d.; 1 item
    Family Record. Copied from the Bible formerly belonging to my uncle, Edward Penington.
    - Family Record, 1701-1771, n.d.; AMsS,
  - Barton, Thomas W., 1813 April 23-1814 April 2; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 April 23; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 April 02; ALS, 4p.
  - Barton, Thomas, 1730-1780, n.d.; 1 item
    - Brief memoir, Ams, 2p.
  - Barton, William P.C., 1786-1856, 1809 August 03-1810 June 27; 4 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 August 3; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 February 06; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 May 07; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 June 27; ALS, 3p.
  - Barton, William, 1754-1817, 1789 April 24-1808 Dec. 27; 9 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1789 April 24-25; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1789; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 July 09; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 October 08; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 November 02; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 December 25; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 April 18; ALS, 3p.
      B.S.B requesting that his brother keep an eye on botanist Frederick Pursh who he feels drinks too much.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September 27; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 February 15; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 December 27; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 January 09; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 May 10; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 April 08; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 June 27; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 July 24; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 March 05; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 March 11; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 June 10; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 June 19; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 3p.
  - Bartram, James Howell, 1783-1818, 1808 February 15; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Bartram, John, 1743-1812, 1812 March 24; 4 items
    - to William Prince 1766-1842, 1812 March 24; Photocopy, 1p.
    - to William Prince, 1812 March 24; TL, 1p.
      Typed version of same letter
    - to William Prince, 1812 March 24; Photocopy, 1p.
      Photocopy of back of letter to Prince showing address.
    - Mrs. Roy Arthur Hunt, n.d.; Business Card, 1 card
  - Bartram, William, 1739-1823, 1791 March -1800 July 11; 7 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1791 March; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1791 September; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 September 23-25; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 January 11; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 March 3; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1800 April 3; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1800 July 11; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 July 13; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 August; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 August 23; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 September 27; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 October 25; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 January 02; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 May 25; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 November 19; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 December 13; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 January 23; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 February 18; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 March 07; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 November 24; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 November 30; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 November 30; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 December 31; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 December 13; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 September 14; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Bassett, Erastus, 1805 July 17; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Batty, Robert C., 1763-1849, 1809 January 25-n.d.; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 January 25; ALS, 11 p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; Ams, 2p.
      rough draft of 11 p. letter to Batty
  - Baum, John, 1809 April 18; 1 item, 2 p.
  - Bayly, Lewis, 1809 November 15-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 November 15; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
  - Beasley, Peter J., 1813 October 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Beatty, John, 1749-1826, 1808 April 19-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 April 19; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
      response to Beatty's letter regarding whether or not the specimen that Beatty had sent was a "Colombo."
  - Bedford, John R., 1808 February 08; 1 item, 2p.
  - Belknap, Jeremy, 1744-1798, 1794 November 23; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Bell, John, 1763-1820, 1809 January 15; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Bell, Mrs. John, 1809 July 19; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Bensell, George, 1804 November 05; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Bigelow, Jacob, 1786-1879, 1811 October 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Birch & Small, 1808 January 17; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Black, John, 1803 February 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Blanchet, F., 1776-1830, 1800 November 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
      In French.
  - Bohannan, R. L., 1814 October 29; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Bohlen, John, 1770-1850, 1807 July 29; 1 item
    Barely legible but possibly a request from a student since Barton has scrawled a note on the reverse about a botany class requirement.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1 p.
  - Bosc, Louis-Augustin-Guillaume, 1759-1828, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
      Fragment of a letter written in French.
  - Bott, John B., 1814 January 14; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Bowles, Richard C., 1812 May 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Bozman, George, 1812 March 27-1812 June 1; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 March 27; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 June 1; ALS, 1p.
  - Brackenridge, W., 1801 July 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Bradbury, John, 1810 March 15-1810 Sept. 13; 3 items
    - to Samuel Bridge, 1810 March 15; ALS, 3p.
    - to Samuel Bridge, 1810 August 20; ALS, 3p.
    - to Samuel Bridge, 1810 September 13; ALS, 2p.
  - Bradford, Thomas, 1804 July 09; 1 item
    - to the Medical Professors in the University of Pennsylvania, ALS, 6p.
  - Brickell, John, 1749-1809, 1807 August 08-1807 Nov. 25; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 August 08; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 September 07; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 November 25; ALS, 3p.
  - Briggs, Robert, 1815 January 06; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Brooke, Francis, 1763-1857, 1815 February 14; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Brown, C., 1792 November 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Brown, Mr., 1814 March 07-1814 Oct. 27; 3 items
    Three barely legible items to Barton's printer.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 March 07; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 October 27; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Brown, Richard, 1807 October 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Brown, Samuel, 1769-1830, 1808 March 27; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Browne, William, 1814 December 16; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Browul, Thomas, 1812 March 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1 p.
  - Bruce, Archibald, 1777-1818, 1814 November 09-1815 March 25; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 November 02; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 25; ALS, 2p.
  - Bruce, Professor, 1810 September 08; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Bruse, Edward, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Bryant, A., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Bullard, A., 1809 August 08; 1 item
    Bullard described the character of two physicians apparently at Barton's request.
    - to Thomas G. Keegan, ALS, 3p.
  - Bundo, Augustus Frederic de, 1812 April 20; 1 item
    Seeking assistance from Barton in procuring employment.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Burke, Joseph, 1814 November 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Burns, James, 1810 May 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Cabell, Robert B., 1806 April 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Calhoun, Samuel, d. 1841, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Callanery, George, 1808 April 22; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Cameron, J. A., 1814 October 20; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Campman, Frederick, Jr., 1814 November 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1 p.
  - Carey, W., 1811 April 27; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Carter, Charles W., 1815 June 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 4p.
  - Carter, Robert, 1802 March 1-1803 Oct. 1; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 March 1+; ALS, 2 p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 October 1; ALS, 3p.
  - Casey, John A., 1809 February 1-1813 Sept. 1; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 February 1; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 September 1; ALS, 2p.
  - Cathrall, Isaac, 1764-1819, 1794 August 19; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Chambers, Campbell, 1807 March 24-1808 May 30; 4 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 March 24; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 May 30; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; Ams, 2P.
  - Channing, Walter, 1786-1876, 1810 May -1811 Sept. 29; 3 letters
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 May; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 March 20; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 September 29; ALS, 2p.
  - Chapman, Nathaniel, 1780-1853, 1814 November 10-1815 March 5; 4 items
    University-related material.
    - to unknown, 1814 November 10; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 05; ALS, 2p.
    - to Mr.Whitlocke, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ADS, 1 p.
  - Cheston, Emily R., 1936 March 06; 2 items
    - Catalogue of exhibits, 1931 June 5-6; PrD, 14 p.
    - to Mrs. Delafield, 1936 March 06; ALS, 3p.
      about looking up info on Mrs. William Smith Barton
  - Claiborne, William, 1775-1817, 1812 August 17; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Clinton, DeWitt, 1769-1828, 1815 February 28-1815 Feb. ?; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 February; LS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 February 15; ALS, 1p.
      rough draft of letter.
  - Cocke, James, 1780-1813, 1809 July 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Cocke, Richard, 1814 December 14; 1 item
    Regarding an appointment in Philadelphia
    - to Dr. William Boswell, ALS, 3p.
  - College Royal de Sanite a` Stockholm, 1814 October 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, AMsS, 2p.
      Offering an honorary membership into the Royal Society.
  - Collin, Nicholas, 1745-1831, 1804 January 09-1814 Feb. 8; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 January 09; ALS, 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 May 02; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 February 08; ALS, 3p.
  - Collins & Perkins, 1808 May 21-1808 Oct. 22; 2 items
    Regarding the cost of publishing and selling Barton's books.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 May 21; ALS, 2p.
  - Collins, Zacheus, 1764-1831, 1803 April 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Conklin, Edwin G., 1941 December 30-1942 Feb. 16; 5 items
    Regarding Mrs. Delafield's Barton papers.
    - to General and Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1941 December 30; TLS, 1p.
    - A.P.S. notice of Midwinter Meeting, 1941 December 30; TMsCy, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 13; TLS, 1p.
    - Program for A.P.S. Midwinter Meeting, 1942 February 13-14; Program, 4p.
    - 1942 February 16, TLS, 1p.
  - Conrad, John, 1803 January 10-1806 Aug. 30; 11 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 January 10; ANS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 June 1; ANS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 February 24; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 May 08; ANS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 May 17; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 June 15; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 July 25; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 August 30; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 January 19; ANS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
  - Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864, 1812 February 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Coxe, Richard, 1814 May 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Craig, Haniety, 1807 December 24; 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Cramer, Samuel J., 1813 October 23-1814 Oct.29; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 October 29; ALS, 1p.
  - Crawford, John, 1746-1813, 1807 August 06-1811 Nov. 3; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 August 06; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 November 3; ALS, 2p.
  - Crommelin, B. J., n.d.; 1item
    The letter is virtually unreadable due to fading. The names provided were on the previous folder.
    - to T.T.Zeylemaker, ALS, 2p.
  - Crosbey, Thomas B., 1815 April 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Crukshank, Joseph, 1746-1836, 1808 June 03; 1 item
    regarding prize medals.
    - to Isaac Snowden, ALS, 1p.
  - Cunningham, M., 1808 February 13; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Currie, William, 1811 February 1-1811 Feb. 19; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 February 1; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 February 19; ALS, 3p.
  - Curtis, H., n.d.; 1 item
    About seeking absolution
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Custis, Peter, 1806 June 1-1808 Oct. 29; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 June 1; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 May 21; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808; ALS, 3p.
  - Cutbush, James, 1788-1823, 1809 November 1-1810 March 28; 5 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 November 1; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 March 28; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Cutler, Manasseh, 1742-1823, 1792 November 19; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Dade, Francis, 1814 January 28-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 January 28; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Dareh, S., n.d.; 1 item
    Regarding a patient's care.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Darlington, William, 1782-1863, 1804 November 12-1807 Dec. 17; 4 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 November 12; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 December 17; ALS, 2p.
    - Excerpt from Medical Diary, Chester County Historical Society, 1804-13; CMs, 2p.
  - Davenport, Thomas, 1807 March 26; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Davis, Isaac, 1810 March 12-1810 March 15; 1 item
    Davis requested that he be granted his medical degree without attending the commentment; Barton's reply seemed to be a denial of that request.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 March 12; ALS, 3p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 March 15; ANS, 1p.
  - Davis, John, 1802 February 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - DeBritton, S., 1804 October 16; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Delafield, Violetta and John Ross, 1937 January 13-1937 March 31; 3 items
    - from The Garden Club of America, 1937 January 13; TLS, 1p.
    - from The Garden Club of America, 1937 January 16; TLS, 1p.
    - from Gordon Dunthorne, 1937 March 31; ALS, 2p.
  - Delafield, Violetta, 1936 June 25-1936 July 17; 4 items
    Correspondence requesting background information on Mrs. Benjamin Smith Barton and the Pennington family.
    - to Edward Rush Duer, 1936 June 25; TL, 1p.
    - to Dr. Albert Cook Myers, 1936 July 17; TL, 1p.
    - from Laura E. Hanson, 1937 January 04; TLS, 1p.
    - from C. Stuart Gager, 1937 January 14; TLS, 1 p.
    - from Harvey Cushing, 1937 January 27; TLS, 1p.
    - from Wm. W. Wilson, 1937 April 12; ALS, 3 p.
    - from W. L. McAtee, 1937 April 26; TLS, 1 p.
    - from W. L. McAtee, 1937 May 04; TLS, 1 p.
    - from Mary D. Richards, 1937 May 11; ALS, 2 p.
    - from Harvey Cushing, 1938 January 06; TLS, 1 p.
    - from Laura E. Hanson, 1938 January 10; TLS, 1p.
    - Article about first flower show, n.d.; newspaper clipping, 1p.
    - Montgomery Place, Annandale on Hudson, N.Y., Postcard, 1 postcard
  - Denke, Christian Frederich Heinrich, 1811 April 26; 1 item
    Regarding a botanical book borrowed by Denke.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - DeNormandie, John H., 1786, February 05-n.d.; 3 items
    - to Amos Gregg, 1786 February 05; ALS, 2p.
    - to Amos Gregg, n.d.; ALS, 3p.
    - to Amos Gregg, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
  - Dickerson, Aaron, 1809 October 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Dickinson, A., 1811 January 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1 p.
  - Dickson, R., 1810 September 09; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Dobson, Thomas, 1804 June 16; 1 item
    - to all whom it may concern, ADS, 1p.
      Certificate of William & Thomas Bradford's offer to publish medical thesis (University of Pennsylvania)
  - Dorsey, P., 1806 January 02; 1 item
    - to Medical Professors of the University, ALS, 2p.
  - Drake, Daniel, 1785-1852, 1814 September 26; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Drayton, John, 1766-1822, 1803 June 22; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Dudley, Benjamin Winslow, 1785-1870, 1809 February 21; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Duffield, Samuel, 1807 June 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, Als, 2p.
  - Dunbar, Robert, 1803 February 19; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Dunbar, William to Garret Elliot Pendergast, 1803 March 31; ALS, 1p.
  - DuPont, Pierre S., 1801 August 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Duvall, Grafton, 1812 August 10; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Dyer, Thomas, 1873 January 11; 1 item
    - to unknown, ALS, 4p.
      Not clear to which member of the Barton family Dyer has written but he does make a reference to "Mrs. Barton."
  - Eddy, Caspar Wistar, 1761-1818, 1814; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
      about enlisting Baron's help in writing a botanical dictionary
  - Eliot, Ephraim, n.d.; 1 item
    - to George C. Shattuck, ALS, 4p.
  - Eliot, John, 1799 April 17-1805 Nov. 19; 3 items
    Eliot wrote primarily of the "collections."